CARLOS CARDENAS

- +51 940584307
- www.linkedin.com/in/carloscardenasf
- https://github.com/unimauro

DevOps, Machine Learning, Open Source and Hacking Expert. More than fifteen years in software engineering, application management and manages service in industries like telecommunications, banking, defense, education and government. Friendly leadership, self-taught, creative and systemic vision. Focus on results, efficiency and autonomy.

EXPERIENCE

HUAWEI

Senior Software Engineer

2015 - 2019

- TUGO and SVA manage service for Telefónica Perú with 2 MM and 10 MM subscribers, OnPremise and Cloud base and Oracle instances.
- · ClaroVideo implemented 1M users, role devops engineer deployed in GCP, Huawei Cloud.
- Claro's IPCC Contact Center with 30 million calls by month; roles delivery engineer, senior architect in manage service reducing 70% the workload. Tools used Python 3.X, Scikit-learn, R dplyr, React implementing CI/CD.

GOOGLE CODE SUMMER 2018 - SUGARLABS.

Mentor Developer

2018

Design a CI/CD integration in deploy process application for Sugar Labs and scrapping tool to update information in short wikipedia offline. Tools: python 3.X, Go, VUE.js in GCP.

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES PERU.

Software Engineer

2012 - 2014

- Software Engineer inside strategic project Rimac Seguros and Strategic Brokers, improving by 50% the processing of information. Working in Oracle, Python 2.X and ExtJs in OnPremise.
- Improved UX Research and deployment GUI framework in CREA Project with BCP improvement the usability and accessibility. Technologies Jquery, Jenkins, Java, Spring, UNIX.

GOOGLE CODE SUMMER 2012 - ASCEND4.

Developer

2012

• Migration Project ASCEND4 mathematical simulator for Apple Mac OSX platforms, xcode, python 2.X and fortran.

MUNICIPALIDAD DE MIRAFLORES- OFICINA DE CONTROL INTERNO

Systems Engineering Specialist

2012

• Auditor of Special Examination Management Systems and Information Technology of the municipality in terms of IT processes and best practices Cobit, OIC Training staff in ACL, IDEA, Google Docs, Systems Audit and Strategic Planning.

UNIVERSIDAD DE PIURA - MARINA DE GUERRA DEL PERÚ

Software Engineer

2010 - 2011

Sub Project Manager of Navigational Aids Systems.

• Project management valued at over three million soles. Drop cost of software licenses by 80%.

UNIVERSIDAD PARTICULAR CAYETANO HEREDIA

Software Engineer

2009 - 2010

- 100% implementation of the project management and monitoring of the technological architecture reducing by 70% the time of generation IT process indicators.
- Implementation Institutional Learning Management System, autonomous and scalable, reducing by 80% the cost of administration of maintenance services.

MCD CONSULTING S.A.C

Software Engineer

2009

• 300% reduction in processing time and transfer between business systems and distribution management. Improved processes and claim application in electric service to 50% by reducing the time of reporting.

CEMENTO PACASMAYO S.A.A.

Assistant in Information Technology Management

• Process Improvement Sales and Orders Release of SAP ERP with intelligent mobile terminals that reduced response time by 40%.

SUPER INTENDENCIA NACIONAL DE ADMINISTRACION TRIBURATIA - SUNAT

Assistant Management Planning and Control Conventions 2007 - 2008 Responsible for monitoring and controlling the Institutional Strategic Plan.

• Improved management indicators that contributed to reduce by 50% the time of data extraction.

NATIONAL BANK PERU

Developer 2002 - 2003

Develop and implement the project Institutional Web Portal National Bank.

• Managing and Implementing Web Portal Projects 100%, with over 6 million visitors a per month and an annual growth of 7%. Design technology architecture of the institutional Intranet reducing by 60% the implementation and maintenance costs.

EDUCATION

EBOOKIION	
QISKIT GLOBAL SUMMER SCHOOL	2020-2020
Quantum Computer by IBM with Qiskit Tools	
MIT edX MicroMasters	
Program Statistic and Data Science	2019-2021
HARVARD edX	
Data Science Professional Certificate	2019-2020
CENTRUM PONTIFICIA UNIVERSIDAD CATÓLICA DEL PERÚ	
Master Business Administration	2010-2012
UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL DE INGENIERIA	
System Engineering	1999-2008

PUBLICATIONS AND AWARDS

- Google Mentor Summit Summer of Code 2014. San José California.
- Interaction 2009: Usability Pilot Activities in OLPC and Classmate Sugar with children 5 years old. Colombia.
- HCII 2009: Evaluating the Usability of Desktop of the OLPC Sugar and Interface Children in Distributed Applications. CA/US.
- Thesis: Assessing Usability Engineering OLPC.
- Third Place in Congress INTERCOM. Usability in Laptops for Kids.
- CONEIS XIII 2005. Multimedia Streaming Live CD ACUNIX for Alternative Communication Systems.

OTHER PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

- •Freelance in AWS, GCP, Azure and Fullstack LAMP, MERN.
- •Professor in Operative System course in National University of Engineering 2015.
- •Professor in E-Business Application course in National University of Engineering 2009.

KNOWLEDGE AND TECHNICAL TOOLS

Operating Systems: GNU / Linux, Windows, Solaris, AS400. Cloud: AWS, AZURE, Google Cloud Platform, Huawei Cloud y OpenStack. Containers: Kubernetes, Docker, Chroot. Programming: Golang, Python, R, C/C++, JavaScript, PHP,Java. Framework: CakePhp, Symfony, Laravel, Yii. Ruby, Perl, VS.Net, SAP ABAP, C Object, Scala. Librerías: React, NodeJS, AngularJS, GraphQL, Django, Scrapy. Laravel, Symfony, RubyOnRails, Spring, Blade, Spark, Kafka. BI: DataStage, Pentaho, RapidMiner, Qlik, JasPerSoft. Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Fox, SQL Server, Oracle. Genexus. Data Science: Tableau, Hadoop, IBM Watson, Machine Learning; Frameworks: Tensor Flow, Keras, PyTorch, Scikit Learn, Blockchain. Modelers: Power Designer, Erwin, Rational. Developer Tool: Eclipse, NetBeans. Statistics. Simulation: SPSS, Promodel, Stella, R, Octave, Matlab. Mobile: Android, IOs Xcode, BlackBerry. Management. Projects: PMI, Scrum, Lean, Pomodoro. NTP: 12207, 17799. COBIT, ITIL, CMMI. Audit: COSO, COSO ERM, SOX, Nagu, IDEA, ACL. Microsoft Project. Process Mapping: BPM, IDEFO, Enterprise Architecture, BPWin.

COURSES

- Coursera, Edx, Udemy, DataCamp, Huawei Learning, LinkedIn Learning.
- ITIL V3 2013, Project Management 2012, Fast Training de QT C++ 2010.